Hello,
你好，
hope everyone had a great, long weekend.
希望大家度过了一个愉快的长周末。
We'll start today is the first lecture of the glass.
今天我们将开始本学期的第一堂课。
During this lecture,
在本次讲座中，
we are going to finish our discussion on threads and processes from last time.
我们将继续上次关于线程和进程的讨论。
And then we are going to start the discussion on file systems.
然后我们将开始对文件系统进行讨论。
In particular, we are going to go over a high level file,
具体来说，我们将讨论一个高级文件。
io and streams.
输入/输出和流。
As always, please.
一如既往，请提供英文文本。
If you have questions asking the q and a I will stop
如果你有问题，请直接提问，我会停下来回答。
periodically during the lecture to answer these questions.
在讲座期间定期回答这些问题。
So is that being said, let's start.
所以说，让我们开始吧。
So we discussed quite a bit of about threads.
所以我们讨论了很多关于线程的内容。
And by now,
到现在为止，
the threads are the execution entity which run
线程是执行实体，用于运行任务。
some code within an address context and or
在地址上下文中的一些代码
within a process.
在一个进程内部。
So this threads in the same address space in the same process,
所以这些线程在同一个进程的相同地址空间中。
share the content of the memory.
共享内存的内容。
This means global variables, heap,
这指的是全局变量、堆、
as well as other resources, like file,
以及其他资源，如文件，
descriptors and other connections.
描述符和其他连接。
And their state are the same time.
它们的状态同时相同。
A thread has each thread has private state,
每个线程都有私有状态。
and that state capture the execution of a particular and this
并且该状态捕获了特定执行的过程
information is stored in what they called thread control block.
信息存储在所谓的线程控制块中。
Like we discussed in the past,
正如我们之前讨论过的，
it contains the cpu registers,
它包含了CPU寄存器。
including the program counters and the execution stack.
包括程序计数器和执行栈。
Now next, we are going to talk a little bit more about the execution stack.
接下来，我们将更详细地讨论执行栈。
What does it contain?
它包含什么内容？
Why is it part of the thread privacy?
为什么这是线程隐私的一部分？
At the high level, the execution stack stores?
在高层次上，执行栈存储了什么？
The parameters arguments passed only call a function and the return address
参数是传递给函数的参数和返回地址。
from that function.
从那个函数中。
Here is a very simple example.
这是一个非常简单的例子。
On the left hand side,
在左侧
you have three functions,
你有三个函数，
ab and c and on the left,
在左边的ab和c上，
we have some labels.
我们有一些标签。
And they think about this label like addresses for the particular line
他们将这个标签视为特定行的地址。
in the code.
在代码中。
And the red rectangle illustrates the code,
而红色矩形表示了代码，
the line we are currently executing.
我们当前正在执行的行。
So let's start by invoking function a with argument one.
那么让我们从使用参数为一的函数a开始。
Now, you see, on the right hand side, you see the stack.
现在，你看到了，右边是栈。
What happens here?
这里发生了什么？
We push the argument of a on the stack, the value.
我们将a的参数值推入栈中。
It's what?
这是什么？
One.
一。
And then we also pushed the return address after a it's executed.
然后，在执行完之后，我们还将返回地址推入栈中。
The return address here is exit and you can see the exit.
这里的返回地址是exit，你可以看到exit。
It's the address in memory right after a one is okay,
这是一个在内存中紧跟在一个地址之后的地址，没问题。
because stamp is one on execute a then we take this branch and execute b
因为stamp是在执行a之后，我们会执行这个分支并执行b。
when he called b now there is no argument passed to be.
当他调用 b 时，现在没有参数传递给 be。
So on the start, we are only going to push the address.
所以在开始时，我们只需要推送地址。
We need to go back after executing b this is a plus two,
执行完b之后，我们需要回到这里，这是一个加二的操作。
b call c again,
再次调用C函数b。
no argument is passed here to see.
这里没有传递任何参数来查看。
We just wish the return are the return address after the executive.
我们希望返回的是执行完后的返回地址。
See.
看见了。
See, it's calling a again with argument two.
看，它再次调用了带有参数二的函数a。
Now we put the argument on the stack,
现在我们将参数放入堆栈中，
and the return others is you+1 after a of two executed.
在执行两个操作之后，返回值为你加1的其他人。
And now an aids executive stamp with the argument of two,
现在是一枚关于艾滋病的执行文件，附带两个论点。
we are going to run the final,
我们即将进行期末考试。
the others.
其他人。
We are going to run print f we are going to skip calling b
我们将运行打印函数，跳过调用 b。
the output right now,
当前的输出结果是
because stamp is through the printer.
因为邮票是通过打印机印刷的。
Here, you also can see on the bottom,
在这里，你还可以在底部看到。
right out,
立即出发
the outputs being printed.
正在打印的输出结果。
We are going to bring to.
我们打算带来。
Now a finishes be a finish is being executed.
现在一个任务正在执行完成。
Now, we look at that stack where you need to return.
现在，我们来看一下需要返回的堆栈。
So we need to return to c poisson,
所以我们需要返回到C语言的泊松分布函数。
because that was then the next thing,
因为那是接下来要做的事情，
the next line after a two was invoked.
在调用"two"之后的下一行。
Okay?
好的？
Now see it terminates.
现在看它终止了。
So again, we look at the stack where we need to go.
所以再次，我们看一下我们需要去的堆栈。
So we need to go to be+1.
所以我们需要前往be+1。
And now we terminate b so we need to go back to the instruction of right
现在我们终止 b，所以我们需要回到 right 指令的位置。
after bill was invoked.
在调用了Bill之后。
And now this is sprint f but now the tempest one,
现在是sprint f，但现在是tempest版本。
because this is from the first invocation of a you can look also this
因为这是来自a的第一次调用，你也可以查看这个。
at this on the stack.
在堆栈上的这个位置。
Now we are done.
现在我们完成了。
The output is going to be two and one.
输出将是两个和一个。
Okay?
好的？
The stack is extremely important.
栈非常重要。
It holds not only variables,
它不仅保存变量，
and the arguments are returned.
并且返回参数。
The return address after we exit the function.
在我们退出函数后的返回地址。
But in this way,
但是这样的话，
it also allows for recursive writing your recursive programs.
它还允许递归编写递归程序。
Really, this is the key of all modern languages.
实际上，这是所有现代语言的关键。
One thing to note, though,
需要注意的一点是，
is that the stack grows down.
栈是向下增长的。
You start from means you start from high addresses.
"从起始位置开始"意味着你从高地址开始。
Then as we push on the stack,
当我们将数据推入栈时，
the address is going to go down will decrease.
地址将会下降，即减少。
Okay?
好的？
If we look here as a memory layout for to spread which running
如果我们将这里作为一个内存布局来展开运行的话
the same processes in the same process,
相同的进程在同一个进程中，
you see that, again,
你看到了，再次，
here, the two threads,
这里有两个线程，
they share the code,
它们共享代码，
the global data, the heap,
全局数据，堆
but they don't stare the stack,
但是它们不会直接访问栈。
because the stack contains the execution state of that thread.
因为栈包含了线程的执行状态。
We have to set off stacks.
我们需要设置栈。
But now obviously, one question is that when you start these stacks,
但现在显然有一个问题，那就是当你启动这些栈时，
where do you put that?
你把它放在哪里？
Right?
对吗？
Because you need to put them such a way that has enough room to grow.
因为你需要将它们放置在有足够空间生长的地方。
Okay?
好的？
So you need to make sure that you need to live in a room to grow.
所以你需要确保你需要住在一个房间里才能成长。
Also,
另外，
you need to make sure that one stack will not right over another stack so far.
你需要确保一个栈不会覆盖另一个栈太远。
In this case, you should make sure the stack one,
在这种情况下，你应该确保栈是正确的。
as it grows,
随着它的增长，
is not going to go and overwrite stack, too.
也不会去覆盖堆栈。
So how may two questions here?
这里有两个问题吗？
What happens if the threads violates this?
如果线程违反了这个规定会发生什么？
You can answer that on the question and answers thread.
你可以在问题和答案的帖子上回答这个问题。
No answer.
没有回答。
So what happened?
发生了什么事情？
That corruption, second fault.
那个损坏，第二个故障。
Right?
对吗？
Why?
为了方便中文用户理解和阅读，我将英文内容翻译成中文。这样可以提供更好的帮助和支持。
Because if you override a on the start, what happens?
因为如果你在开始时覆盖了a，会发生什么？
Right?
对吗？
If you override,
如果你重写了一个方法，
you can override the return address of a function involved by a particular thread.
你可以覆盖特定线程中涉及的函数的返回地址。
Now you are going to have garbage there,
现在你那里会有垃圾。
and then you are going to go back.
然后你要回去。
You are going to execute some random code.
你将要执行一些随机代码。
We can even try to executing the round of the code
我们甚至可以尝试执行一轮代码的循环。
of a different process or operating system.
来自不同进程或操作系统的
And in case in which are going to get segmentation for,
在需要进行分段的情况下，
how might you catch
你如何捕捉？
violations?
违规行为？
Got pages that's quite sophisticated stack canary.
有一些非常复杂的堆栈保护机制，被称为"堆栈金丝雀"。
So you need, if you can.
所以你需要，如果你能的话。
Yeah, user is very good.
是的，用户非常好。
We can use if there are different mechanics.
如果有不同的机制，我们可以使用。
But fundamentally, you want to make sure that we can use bounds,
但从根本上讲，您希望确保我们可以使用边界。
like we discussed in the past,
正如我们之前讨论过的那样，
each stack is confined to a particular region of memory,
每个栈被限制在特定的内存区域中。
so that you make sure that and you make sure that region,
以便你确保并确保该地区，
its own only by one thread by that particular stack.
只能由一个特定线程在其自己的堆栈上执行。
Right?
对吗？
Then you cannot go out,
那么你就不能出去了。
therefore, you cannot step over as a stock
因此，你不能将其作为股票跨越。
that will add overhead,
这将增加额外开销。
because now you need to check.
因为现在你需要检查。
It also had some memory protection for the stack.
它还对栈进行了一些内存保护。
We are going to talk more about that,
我们将会更详细地讨论这个问题，
and there is a trade off there,
这里存在一个权衡。
but most your questions,
但是大多数你的问题，
your answer to start out of the other corner.
你的答案是从另一个角落开始。
So now,
所以现在，
we are going to touch on a very important aspect,
我们将要涉及一个非常重要的方面，
and we are going to talk about this a lot of times.
我们将会多次讨论这个话题。
And it's not only important.
而且这不仅仅重要。
It's also painful.
这也很痛苦。
And this is it happens because
这是发生的原因。
we want to provide this kind of great abstractions to the programmer
我们希望为程序员提供这种优秀的抽象化能力
in which each thread,
在其中每个线程中，
its own cpu and you want to provide, on one hand,
它自己的CPU，并且你希望在一方面提供，
this obstruction like act like illusionist.
这种阻碍就像魔术师一样行动。
And on the other hand,
另一方面，
in reality,
实际上，
you don't have as many core as a threat you have in order to provide that obstruction,
你没有足够的核心来提供所需的阻塞。
the way you do it,
你的做法方式
like we discuss in the past,
正如我们之前讨论的那样，
is to interleave the threads on a limited number.
是将线程交错执行在有限的数量上。
Okay?
好的？
Now the problem, what is the problem?
现在的问题是什么？
The problem is that if you are interleave the threads,
问题在于如果你交错执行线程，
this means that you need to stop to suspend a thread to run another thread.
这意味着你需要停止挂起一个线程来运行另一个线程。
And seeing the tooth in the threads you are running can share
当你在运行的线程中看到这个问题时，可以分享一下你的想法。
the same address space.
相同的地址空间。
Then they can modify the same location in the memory.
然后他们可以修改内存中的相同位置。
As a result, they can step on each other toes.
因此，他们可能会互相踩到对方的脚趾。
And because you don't know exactly when the threats
因为你不知道威胁发生的确切时间
are going to be interrupted at what instructions to be suspended,
将在哪些指令被中断时被暂停执行？
this kind of interaction is also unpredictable,
这种互动也是不可预测的，
non deterministic.
非确定性的。
So that's the idea.
那就是这个想法。
For instance, this is a piece with us.
例如，这是我们的一部分。
You have three instructions here.
你这里有三条指令。
Now, this is in a thread which at some point will be suspended.
现在，这是在一个线程中，该线程在某个时刻将被挂起。
One possible execution is to go through the completion and all these instructions.
一个可能的执行方式是按顺序执行所有这些指令和完成操作。
But another possible execution is after execute the first instruction,
但是另一个可能的执行顺序是在执行完第一条指令之后，
which is x equals x plus one.
x等于x加一。
The study suspending and as a strategy to run instead,
将学习暂停作为一种策略来代替运行。
or this thread can be suspended after the first instruction
或者在第一条指令之后，该线程可以被挂起。
are going to be executed.
将要被执行。
You can have a myriad of way in the stress italy,
你可以在意大利体验无数种方式来减压。
right?
对的？
Like you see here, see,
就像你在这里看到的一样，看到了吗，
you can also, in some cases,
在某些情况下，你也可以
the stress can each of them go through completion,
每个人都能承受的压力不同，
because they are very short.
因为它们非常简短。
Or if you have enough course,
或者如果你有足够的课程，
then they are not interleaving,
那么它们就不是交错执行的。
because israel is going to run on score.
因为以色列将要依靠分数运行。
Right?
对吗？
But the interesting part is see when they are going to italy.
但有趣的是看他们什么时候去意大利。
Right?
对吗？
And again,
再次，
the point here is that as a programmer,
这里的重点是作为一个程序员，
you do not know when the study suspended,
你不知道学习暂停的时间。
because operating system, in particular,
因为操作系统，特别是
the scheduler has no idea about the semantics of your program,
调度器对于你的程序的语义一无所知。
so you cannot do anything.
所以你什么都做不了。
So from operating system,
所以从操作系统的角度来看，
point of view is a bunch of instructions.
观点是一系列指令。
And at any given time,
在任何给定的时间，
it can,
它可以。
in theory, it can interrupt you.
理论上，它可以打断你。
It can suspend your thread and run another thread instead on the same core.
它可以暂停你的线程，并在同一个核心上运行另一个线程。
Okay?
好的？
So now,
所以现在，
there are 2 kinds of threats you can think in this world.
在这个世界上，你可以思考到两种威胁。
There are threads which modifies different variables so that the variables
有一些线程修改不同的变量，以便使这些变量
they modify,
他们修改，
they are to be joined that independence.
它们将被合并为独立的实体。
And they are going to provide determine these things us,
他们将为我们确定这些事情。
because it doesn't matter when they are suspended.
因为当它们被挂起时并不重要。
They are not going to use the same variables.
他们不会使用相同的变量。
So they are not going to interfere with each other.
所以它们不会相互干扰。
And then there are cooperating threats.
然后还有合作威胁。
And these are the interesting ones and the difficult ones.
这些是有趣的和困难的。
We share state.
我们共享状态。
We share the state.
Now, the goal is how to design a program,
现在的目标是如何设计一个程序。
which is correct.
哪个是正确的。
No matter when a cooperating threads are suspended,
无论合作线程何时被暂停，
you are going to get a predictable,
你将获得一个可预测的结果。
a correct result.
一个正确的结果。
Let's let's take a aaa few simple examples to illustrate the point.
让我们举几个简单的例子来说明这一点。
And by the way,
顺便一提，
when two threads,
当两个线程
interleave and modify the same variables.
交错和修改相同的变量。
Many times we refer to that as race condition,
很多时候我们将其称为竞态条件。
because one thread races against the other thread.
因为一个线程与另一个线程竞争。
Now, in this first example,
现在，在这个第一个例子中，
is to have two threads,
是要有两个线程，
a and b and these threads modify a different variable,
a和b以及这些线程修改了不同的变量。
study modify x that be y this is an example of independent threads here,
研究修改x使其成为y，这是一个独立线程的示例。
because again, they write,
因为再次，他们写道，
they modify and they read different variables.
他们修改和读取不同的变量。
For instance,
例如，
no matter how the scheduler interleaved these threads,
无论调度程序如何交错执行这些线程，
the output for thread a will be always fun.
线程a的输出将始终是"fun"。
But now let me ask you,
但是现在让我问你，
in this example, what is the output?
在这个例子中，输出是什么？
So you have again to threads.
所以你又有了两个线程。
But now they share one variable,
但现在它们共享一个变量，
which is why.
这就是为什么。
Okay?
好的？
Both of them read and more,
他们两个都阅读得很多，而且还有其他的。
but thread b reads and modify y and a reads.
但是线程B读取并修改了y，而线程A读取了y。
Why?
为了方便中文用户理解和阅读，我会将英文内容翻译成中文。这样可以更好地帮助您解决问题和获取所需的信息。
Let's assume initially that x is zero and y zero.
假设初始时，x和y都为零。
The question, in this case,
在这种情况下，问题是
for these cooperative threads,
对于这些协作线程，
what are the possible values of x why don't you take of
x的可能取值是什么，为什么你不考虑它呢？
23 minutes and think and please write down the
23分钟思考并请写下来。
values?
数值？
You believe x can get?
你相信 x 可以实现吗？
Yes, that's correct.
是的，没错。
135.
抱歉，我不明白你的意思。请提供更多的上下文或问题。
That's perfect.
太好了。
Thank you, right?
谢谢，对吗？
So because if the first,
因此，由于第一个原因，
if thread a executes first and the first instruction is executed to completion,
如果线程a首先执行，并且第一条指令被完整执行完成，
then y was zero,
那么y为零，
x would be up.
x将会上升。
But there are other possible executions.
但是还有其他可能的执行方式。
For instance, the first instruction of strategy can execute.
例如，策略的第一条指令可以执行。
Y is equal to.
Y 等于。
And then the instruction of a can execute.
然后a的指令可以执行。
Now, x is y which are set by thread b to choose x will be three.
现在，x是由线程b设置的y，以选择x将是三。
Or thread b can execute all boston instruction first,
或者线程B可以先执行所有的波士顿指令，
and then thread a and if thread big one or execute all instruction first,
然后线程A开始执行，如果线程A是优先级较高的线程，或者执行所有指令的线程。
then y will be four.
那么y将会是四。
So x instead a that is y value of 4 plus 1 is 5,
所以，将x替换为y的值，即4加1等于5。
x is five.
x 是五。
Now, you can see that even in this simple example,
现在，你可以看到即使在这个简单的例子中，
means you are going,
这句话的意思是你要离开。
things are getting complicated when they said share the same value.
当他们说要共享相同的值时，事情变得复杂了。
Now you can imagine that for a more realistic program,
现在你可以想象一下，对于一个更加真实的程序，
this is even much more complex.
这个甚至更加复杂。
If there is a question here,
如果这里有一个问题，
how do threads share a variable?
线程如何共享变量？
If a thread is the unit of execution?
如果一个线程是执行的单位？
Wouldn't local variable be local to be thread?
局部变量不是只对线程本地的吗？
This is a good question,
这是一个很好的问题，
but i'm going to go back here To answer this question.
但是我会回答这个问题。
The answer is here.
答案在这里。
As you can see, it's, again,
正如你所看到的，又是这样，
all threading the same process,
所有线程属于同一个进程。
share the code the data,
分享代码和数据。
go on the file descriptors.
继续处理文件描述符。
Why they don't share are the registers.
为什么他们不共享寄存器。
They don't share the stack,
它们不共享栈。
but the stack only contains the temporary variables,
但是栈只包含临时变量，
the argument which are passed to the functions and the return parameters.
传递给函数的参数和返回参数。
It does.
是的。
A stack does not contain.
栈不包含。
The global variables are in the data segment here.
全局变量在这里位于数据段。
In this example,
在这个例子中，
I just gave one.
我刚刚给了一个。
This we are talking about x and y are global variables.
我们正在讨论的是全局变量 x 和 y。
All the global variables are shared by all the thread in the process.
所有的全局变量都被进程中的所有线程共享。
Going farther.
走得更远。
Let me just go in.
让我进去一下。
There is another question.
还有一个问题。
Let me take this as a do thread share the skip as well,
让我把这个当作一个“do”线程来分享，同时也跳过它。
the thread share the heap as well.
线程也共享堆内存。
So if one thread allocate something on the heap,
那么如果一个线程在堆上分配了一些内存，
it can give the pointer to another thread which can read the data,
它可以将指针传递给另一个线程，该线程可以读取数据。
allocated from the heap,
从堆中分配的
from the day of agree the data allocated by the first threat.
从同意第一个线程分配数据的那一天开始。
How do different processes communicate?
不同进程如何进行通信？
We are going to learn about that.
我们将要学习这个。
They can communicate by reading and writing on the file system.
他们可以通过在文件系统上读写来进行通信。
They can communicate with sockets, pipes.
它们可以通过套接字、管道进行通信。
There are many ways they can communicate,
他们有很多种方式可以进行沟通，
and there is actually also mechanics to provide shared memory between processes.
实际上，还有一种机制可以在进程之间提供共享内存。
We'll talk more about that.
我们会进一步讨论这个问题。
Thanks for your questions.
谢谢你的问题。
Now, if you write a program which you have multiple threads,
现在，如果你编写一个程序，其中包含多个线程，
we share the same the same data,
我们共享相同的数据，
then you need somehow to coordinate among them to make sure that you get
然后你需要以某种方式协调他们，以确保你得到
the same results,
相同的结果
no matter how the threats are intermittent.
无论威胁是如何间歇性的。
Right?
对吗？
So what means you need to synchronize?
所以你需要进行同步的意思是什么？
One to a woman,
给一个女人。
a threat should access what?
威胁应该访问什么？
Right?
对吗？
And aa particular way to think to synchronize that is
一种特定的思考方式来进行同步的方法是
that to make sure that only
这样可以确保只有
one thread is doing one thing at a time.
一个线程一次只能做一件事情。
This is mutual exclusion,
这是互斥。
will have examples.
会有示例。
Another important concept is critical section.
另一个重要的概念是临界区。
You can define a section in the code,
你可以在代码中定义一个区块，
which it's a critical section,
这是一个关键区域。
which this means that section can be only executed by one thread at a time.
这意味着该部分只能由一个线程同时执行。
You cannot have the two threads executing instruction
你不能让两个线程同时执行指令。
from the critical section at a different time at the same time.
在不同的时间同时从临界区访问。
Another way to think about is that from the programmer.of view,
另一种思考方式是从程序员的角度来看，
all the instruction is the critical section.
所有的指令都是临界区。
They are executed sequentially.
它们按顺序执行。
Okay?
好的？
No one else will modify the variables of which are in the critical section
没有其他人会修改临界区中的变量。
from the stripe executing it.
从执行条纹。
And then how do you in for these critical sections?
那么你是如何进入这些临界区的呢？
And again,
再次，
critical section and mutual exclusion out of the two sides of the same coin,
关键区域和互斥是同一个硬币的两面。
you in order to have a critical section,
为了拥有一个临界区，你需要：
need to implement a critical section,
需要实现一个临界区
you need to have mutual exclusion beginnings that whilst thread execute
你需要有互斥的开始，以确保线程执行时的互斥性。
the critical section,
临界区
another thread cannot execute the instruction that could become a section.
另一个线程无法执行可能成为一个临界区的指令。
And then how at the lower level,
然后在较低的层次上，
how you implement a mutual exclusion.
如何实现互斥。
互斥是一种用于保护共享资源免受并发访问的机制。以下是一些常见的互斥实现方法：
1. 临界区：使用临界区（Critical Section）来保护共享资源。在进入临界区之前，线程需要获取一个锁或信号量。一旦线程进入临界区，其他线程将被阻塞，直到该线程离开临界区。
2. 互斥锁：使用互斥锁（Mutex）来实现互斥。互斥锁是一种同步原语，只允许一个线程进入临界区。当一个线程获取到互斥锁时，其他线程将被阻塞，直到该线程释放锁。
3. 信号量：使用信号量（Semaphore）来实现互斥。信号量是一种计数器，用于控制对共享资源的访问。当信号量的值为1时，表示资源可用，线程可以进入临界区。当信号量的值为0时，表示资源已被占用，线程需要等待。
4. 读写锁：使用读写锁（Read-Write Lock）来实现互斥。读写锁允许多个线程同时读取共享资源，但只允许一个线程写入共享资源。当有线程正在写入时，其他线程无法读取或写入。
这些方法都可以实现互斥，但具体选择哪种方法取决于应用程序的需求和性能要求。
And therefore, because section is choosing blocks.
因此，由于部分正在选择块。
Basically,
基本上，
the concept is that when you are going to enter a critical section,
这个概念是当你要进入一个临界区时，
you are going to acquire a lock.
你将要获取一个锁。
Now,
现在，
and everyone who has to enter the critical session has to acquire the law
每个进入关键会话的人都必须遵守规定。
before entering it.
在进入之前。
If you have the lock,
如果你拥有锁，
no one else can under.
没有其他人能够理解。
When you x is a critical section, you release a lock.
当你访问一个临界区时，你释放一个锁。
Okay?
好的？
This locks,
这个锁定了。
operation, like typically,
操作，通常情况下，
it's not acquire and released,
不是获取和释放，
are atomic,
是原子的，
but meaning that something is atomic is that you cannot,
但是"atomic"的意思是指某个操作是原子性的，也就是说你不能够
you cannot be the sad with executing blocker.
你不能对执行阻塞器感到难过。
Choir cannot be suspended in the middle of executing clock,
在执行时钟的过程中，无法暂停合唱团。
acquire the same about local release.
获取相同的本地版本。
And we are going to learn how we are going to implement these logs later.
我们将在后面学习如何实现这些日志。
For the p threads, libraries,
对于p个线程，库函数，
you do have the lock primitive.
你确实有锁原语。
You have a piece of mutex in when you are going to create a me lock,
当你要创建一个"me"锁时，你需要使用一个互斥锁。
and then you can acquire the lock.
然后你可以获取锁。
And by piece thread, mutex lock,
通过分片线程、互斥锁，
and piece thread mutex unlock,
解释：
"and" 是一个逻辑运算符，表示 "和"。
"piece" 在这里指的是 "片段" 或 "部分"。
"thread" 指的是 "线程"，在计算机操作系统中，线程是程序执行的最小单位。
"mutex" 是 "互斥锁" 的缩写，用于控制多个线程对共享资源的访问。
"unlock" 是 "解锁" 的意思，指的是释放互斥锁。
翻译：
"and piece thread mutex unlock" 可以翻译为 "并且片段线程互斥锁解锁"。
you release a lock.
你释放了一个锁。
Okay?
好的？
You are going to do this in homework on here.
你将在这里完成这个作业。
It's a simple example.
这是一个简单的例子。
This is a piece of code from the code I shown last time,
这是我上次展示的代码中的一部分。
in which we apply that we have the critical section here.
在这里我们应用了临界区。
For my common is common plus,
对于我的common是common plus
common plus, common.
常见的加法，常见的。
Sorry, it's a global variable, if you remember.
抱歉，这是一个全局变量，如果你还记得的话。
So now you may ask yourself,
那么现在你可能会问自己，
why do we have?
为什么我们需要它？
It's in that?
在那里吗？
It's just a single line.
这只是一行代码。
Why do you need to protect by locks as these are single line of code?
为什么需要通过锁来保护这些单行代码？
The reason,
原因是，
again, we are going to discuss more about this in the future.
再次强调，我们将在未来进一步讨论这个问题。
This is just a preview.
这只是一个预览。
Is that this line,
这是这一行吗？
my common is equal,
我的常见是相等的。
my is common plus,
我的是Common Plus。
is basically composed by multiple instructions.
基本上由多个指令组成。
Processor instructions.
处理器指令。
Therefore,
因此，
you can be interrupted in the middle of executing this instruction,
在执行这条指令的过程中，你可能会被中断。
is this line of code.
这是一行代码。
And that can lead to inaccurate results.
这可能导致不准确的结果。
Like, for instance, this line,
例如，比如这一行，
what may do is going to access common from the main memory,
主要是从主存中访问共享资源。
bring it in a register.
将其存入一个寄存器中。
I'd want to that value,
我想获取那个值。
and then store the value back in the memory.
然后将该值存回内存中。
If you are interrupted,
如果你被打断了，
after you brought the value in of the memory of the common in register,
在将共享内存中的值加载到寄存器后，
right?
对的？
And someone else read and write it.
还有其他人来阅读和写入它。
When you are going to be resume execution,
当你准备恢复执行时，
you are going to execute the old value,
你将要执行旧值。
which is the registers.
寄存器是什么。
And then write it back.
然后将其写回。
You can override the value of a different thread.
你可以覆盖其他线程的值。
Another way to another primitive besides lock.
除了锁之外，还有另一种原语的方式。
And again, don't tell you are going to talk more about.
再次强调，不要告诉你会多说些什么。
This is just to give you a sense.
这只是为了让你有个概念。
And also because you are going to use in you have to deal with this
而且因为你要使用它，所以你必须处理这个问题。
in homework one.
在作业一中。
Another way to implement locks is similar force.
另一种实现锁的方式类似于强制。
Think about the generalized locks.
思考一下广义锁。
This was defined by diaspora.
这是由散居社区定义的。
One of the parents of computer science,
计算机科学的创始人之一，
all the way in 60s, yours.
在60年代一路走来，属于你的。
This is also amazing organization primitive using original unix and windows.
这也是使用原始的Unix和Windows的令人惊叹的组织原语。
Okay?
好的？
The way to think about this,
对此的思考方式是，
you have these two primitives,
你有这两个原语，
b and b they be comes from program to test,
b和b是来自测试程序的。
and we were hogan to increment from dutch dash that I was a dutch,
我们本来打算从荷兰开始逐步增加，因为我是荷兰人。
was dutch.
是荷兰人。
Basically, the way they are working is that p thought
基本上，他们的工作方式是这样的：p认为
tries to decrement.
尝试递减。
And if the value of the semaphore is zero, then it blocks.
如果信号量的值为零，则会阻塞。
It's waiting for that value for the center,
它正在等待中心的值。
for to be increment.
为了递增。
And if one is increment,
如果其中一个被增加了，
it's unlocked.
它已解锁。
And is the great and the value is determined.
这是伟大的，价值是由它决定的。
And we it's increment is the value of the semaphore.
当我们对信号量进行增加操作时，它的值会增加。
And if there is any p waiting b is going to signal to it,
如果有任何等待的进程p，b将会向它发送信号。
so it can decrement and continue.
所以它可以递减并继续执行。
Here is a piece of code which shows you how thread join is implemented.
这是一段代码，展示了如何实现线程的加入（join）功能。
You remember,
你记得，
for the third join means that I am waiting for a thread to finish.
第三个join表示我正在等待一个线程完成。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
basically, the thread join is implementing are doing some of four down.
基本上，线程的join实现了四个主要功能。
The similar for it seem it's set one.
类似的东西似乎已经设置好了。
And this is the critical circle section, right?
这是关键区域的部分，对吗？
Is like in something like your summer fall down.
就像是你的夏天坠落一样。
What does that mean here?
这在这里是什么意思？
Some are for down.
有些是用于下降的。
Here is going to decline the summer for one.
这里将要拒绝一个夏季。
From 1 to 0, you are going to have zero.
从1到0，你将会得到零。
You are going to enter the critical section.
你即将进入临界区。
Notice that, again, this part,
请注意，再次强调，这部分，
the mutual exclusion part is implemented by all the threats,
互斥部分由所有线程实现。
right?
对的？
And only one thread can enter the critical section.
只有一个线程可以进入临界区。
Right?
对吗？
Because one, it wants one system once thread entered this critical section.
因为它希望在一个系统中，一旦一个线程进入了这个临界区域。
Everyone?
大家？
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
I got disconnected.
我断线了。
Please add the questions,
请添加问题。
and let me try to answer the questions.
让我来尝试回答这些问题。
Again, sorry about that them up.
再次抱歉让他们失望。
Okay.
好的。
So please,
所以，请
I there are a few questions I haven't answered and I no longer see
我还有几个问题没有回答，但我现在看不到了。
them after reconnecting.
重新连接后，将它们恢复。
So please ask them again.
所以请再问一次。
So let's move on.
那么我们继续吧。
Okay?
好的？
Basically, here,
基本上，在这里，
if we want to implement the signaling for the strategy join,
如果我们想要实现策略加入的信号传递，
like I mentioned earlier,
正如我之前提到的，
you can use a semi force.
你可以使用半强制。
When a straight finishes,
当一条直线完成时，
he just bring the summer for up.
他只是为我们带来了夏天。
Therefore,
因此，
okay, so sorry, thank you taking your step back.
没关系，很抱歉，谢谢你的退让。
In this particular.
在这个特定的情况下。
So initially,
最初，
what we saw is a previous example.
我们所看到的是一个之前的例子。
I don't know how much you lost from what I said.
我不知道你从我说的话中损失了多少。
We are implementing a critical section.
我们正在实现一个临界区。
This is the first example about using similar force to implement
这是关于使用类似力来实现的第一个示例。
the critical section where only once thread at a time can execute
临界区是指只允许一个线程执行的部分
in the critical section.
在临界区。
The second example is implement on the thread join,
第二个例子是使用线程的join方法实现的。
and with the thread join,
使用线程的join方法，
the way we implemented it is like, first of all,
我们的实现方式是这样的，首先，
the semaphore now it's initialize to zero, not one.
信号量现在被初始化为零，而不是一。
And when a threat finish,
当威胁结束时，
it is is going to increment the semaphore right?
它将要增加信号量，对吗？
The main thread which created the other threads and ways for the stress to finish,
主线程创建了其他线程，并提供了完成压力的方式。
is going only to call some up or down.
只会调用一些向上或向下的操作。
And initially,
最初，
if the threat no threat has finished,
如果威胁已经结束，
the sum of four is zero and remains zero,
四个数的和为零，并且保持为零。
the same the main thread calling thread join is blocked.
相同的主线程调用线程的join被阻塞。
When I started finishes,
当我开始完成时，
then this is decrement it,
那么这就是将其减少。
which is exactly the behavior you want.
这正是你想要的行为。
So there is one connection,
所以有一个连接，
one question.
一个问题。
Some of us don't have an owner like locks,
我们中的一些人没有像锁一样的所有者
do I this is depends on the implementation,
这取决于具体的实现。
is nothing fundamental about blocks,
块本身没有什么根本性的东西。
also enough for us to have an owner.
我们拥有一个所有者已经足够了。
The one,
一个
the only important things,
唯一重要的事情是，
even for locks,
即使是对于锁来说，
is to make sure that only one thread can get a lock at a given time.
是为了确保在给定时间内只有一个线程可以获得锁。
In our context, the next question, in our context,
在我们的背景下，下一个问题，在我们的背景下，
you can potentially have infinitely many threads, right?
你可以潜在地拥有无限多的线程，对吗？
Then was the difference between our concept of threat
那么我们对威胁概念的理解有何不同呢？
and the limited harder threats.
以及更加有限的困难威胁。
Like acpu has 12 courts or 24 threats.
像一个CPU有12个核心或者24个线程。
It's, again, the thread is the programming construct,
再次强调，线程是一种编程结构，
right?
对的？
And you can have infinitely an infinite number,
你可以拥有无限多个无限的数量。
not an infinite,
不是无限的。
nothing can be infinite here.
这里没有什么是无限的。
But you can have a very large number of threats, let's say, 1,000.
但是你可能会面临非常多的威胁，比如说1,000个。
But at the same time, you have four cores and four and one core,
但同时，你有四个核心和四个加一核心。
say it can execute only one side at a time.
它一次只能执行一边。
Right?
对吗？
So basically,
基本上，
the difference here is that, again,
这里的区别在于，再次，
the thread is a programming construct,
线程是一种编程构造，
is what you create in a program.
程序中你所创建的东西。
And a core.
还有一个核心。
It's what you have physically, right?
这是你实际拥有的东西，对吗？
And you need to deal with our constraints.
而且你需要处理我们的限制。
You can run at a given time, for example, only for a stretch.
你可以在指定的时间运行，例如，只运行一段时间。
That's how you need to design their living to map all these 1,000 threads.
这就是你需要设计他们的生活方式来映射这1,000个线程的方式。
You have at the application level as a programmer level to this four course.
作为一个程序员，你在应用层面上有这四门课程的水平。
And the way to do it, like I mentioned many times by interleaving,
就像我多次提到的那样，通过交错的方式来完成。
by running a thread for a little bit and running another thread and so forth.
通过运行一个线程一段时间，然后运行另一个线程，依此类推。
Maybe there's a question here.
也许这里有一个问题。
It's also related with what the concept of hypothetic.
这也与假设的概念有关。
Okay?
好的？
Now hyper threading we haven't talked,
现在我们还没有讨论超线程技术。
and we are not going to talk during the class by hyper threading.
我们在课堂上不会讨论超线程。
It is a harder concept.
这是一个较难的概念。
And this allows accord to execute a certain time,
这样可以让accord在特定的时间执行。
but it doesn't modify the fact that the number of threads that the harbor
但这并不改变港口所能容纳的线程数量的事实
can run
可以运行
at a given time is limited.
在给定的时间内是有限的。
It will only say that instead of running,
它只会显示而不会运行，
I I have four cores instead of running 4/3 of the time.
我有四个核心，而不是运行4/3的时间。
Now I can run 1/3 of the time.
现在我可以运行的时间是三分之一。
So there is no fundamental difference.
所以没有根本的区别。
Let's move on.
让我们继续吧。
We are the so now we talk about threads.
我们现在来讨论线程。
Now let's look a little bit step back and talk more about our processes.
现在让我们稍微退后一步，更多地谈谈我们的进程。
The process is an environment in which you execute your code and have
进程是一个执行代码并具有环境的实体。
the restricted rights.
受限权利。
So process, remember,
所以进程，记住，
contains one or more threads,
包含一个或多个线程
because a stress as a unit of execution and a single other space,
因为一个进程作为执行的单位和一个单独的内存空间，
the other space is protected from other spaces,
其他空间受到其他空间的保护。
owned by other processes.
被其他进程所拥有。
It also owns a file process,
它还拥有一个文件进程。
also own the resources like file descriptors,
还拥有像文件描述符这样的资源，
network connection.
网络连接。
Okay?
好的？
When you run a program,
当你运行一个程序时，
the program execute within a process.
程序在一个进程中执行。
And an application like we're discussing the past,
而且，就像我们之前讨论过的那样，一个应用程序，
can iran on more than one processes can have more than on processes?
伊朗可以在多个进程上运行吗？可以拥有多个进程吗？
Right?
对吗？
Remember, is an example about trivial example is facebook.
记住，这只是一个关于微不足道的例子，以Facebook为例。
It's one application,
这是一个应用程序。
but there are many processes that are not even running
但是有很多进程甚至没有在运行。
onto the same machine that running on different measures.
在同一台机器上运行在不同度量上的情况下。
Right?
对吗？
In all of them and in operating systems,
在所有这些中以及操作系统中，
today's operating systems,
今天的操作系统，
everything which turns out outside the kernel,
一切在内核之外发生的事情，
it's a process.
这是一个进程。
The kernel, if you remember, is a part of the operating system,
如果你还记得的话，内核是操作系统的一部分。
which is based always a resident in the memory.
这是指始终驻留在内存中的操作系统。
Now,
现在，
the processes have a similar mechanism to create other processes.
进程具有类似的机制来创建其他进程。
You also have for processes,
你还有四个进程。
fork in command to create another process.
在命令中使用fork创建另一个进程。
But what is the fundamental difference between forking a process
但是分叉进程和创建进程的根本区别是什么？
or forking or creating a new threat?
还是分叉或创建一个新的线程？
The fundamental difference is that when you create a new thread that thread,
基本的区别在于，当你创建一个新的线程时，该线程
like we just discussed,
就像我们刚刚讨论的那样，
share the code and the global variables and other resources
分享代码、全局变量和其他资源
with the other thread in the same process,
与同一进程中的其他线程一起，
the thread which created it.
创建它的线程。
But in the case of a process,
但是对于一个进程来说，
if a process creates another process,
如果一个进程创建了另一个进程，
the new processes and new address that are
新的进程和新的地址
different other space and share nothing with the process which created it
不同的其他空间，并且与创建它的进程不共享任何内容
in order to go around this limitation,
为了绕过这个限制，
while the fork is doing it,
在fork执行时，
copies the everything the current process of the parent process had
复制当前进程的父进程的所有内容
to the child process.
给子进程。
It copies a crowd,
它复制了一群人。
it copies the resources with the process who created another process is
它将资源与创建另一个进程的进程一起复制。
a new process.
一个新的进程。
Okay?
好的？
If a process one,
如果一个进程一，
crisis process two,
危机处理二，
using fork,
使用fork函数，
the for corporation will copy the code and the access to the resources
该公司将复制代码并访问资源。
that process one has to process two.
进程一必须处理进程二。
Therefore, the process to execute the same code.
因此，执行相同代码的过程。
And now, when you call fork,
现在，当你调用fork函数时，
it returns immediately.
它立即返回。
And it's,
而且，
depending the value it returns,
根据它返回的值，
depends on whether the fork it's in the child process or is a parent process.
这取决于fork是在子进程中还是在父进程中。
If it's a parent processor for returns the process identifier of the child.
如果它是一个父处理器，则返回子进程的进程标识符。
If it's in the child process,
如果它在子进程中，
it returns zero.
它返回零。
If it's a rise and zero,
如果是上升和零,
then it's an error.
那么这就是一个错误。
Now, let's look at this simple example.
现在，让我们来看一个简单的例子。
So you basically called fork here,
所以你在这里基本上调用了fork函数。
and it returns cpid and if cpid is zero,
它返回 cpid，如果 cpid 是零，
you do something and bbc cpid equals zero,
当你执行某个操作时，BBC的CPID等于零。
you do something else again when you call fork.
当你调用fork时，你又做了一些其他的事情。
And you in this process,
在这个过程中，你也参与其中，
this runs into a process.
这会进入一个进程。
A new process is created,
创建了一个新的进程。
and that new process is going to run the same code,
而且这个新进程将运行相同的代码，
because the code will be copied in the new process.
因为代码将被复制到新的进程中。
Is the first process,
第一个进程是
which is apparent process.
明显的进程是指在系统中可见的正在运行的进程。
The cpid will be the identifier of a child process.
cpid将是子进程的标识符。
It'll be greater than zero.
它将大于零。
This is what you are going to be to happen in the parent process.
这是父进程即将发生的事情。
The alice branch,
Alice 分支，
the cpid zero happen and will be run.
CPID为零的进程发生并将被执行。
This instruction will be run in the child process.
这条指令将在子进程中运行。
What you are going to get here,
在这里，你将会得到什么
right?
对的？
What is the output you are going to see?
你将会看到什么输出？
You are going to get from this card I
你将从这张卡中获得我
need,
需要
but you should try it.
但是你应该试一试。
So very likely,
非常有可能，
what will happen here?
这里会发生什么？
You are going to see the first process of parents say you can see the
你将要看到父进程的第一个输出，它说你可以看到。
parent will see parent 1234,
家长将看到家长1234。
top to ten.
从上到下的前十名。
And then from,
然后从
ii see that there are some answers better and 10 times.
我看到有一些答案比其他答案好10倍。
And not the.
而不是。
Now the parent will do it 10 times,
现在父进程将执行这个操作10次，
and the child will do 10 times.
孩子将会做10次。
And this is what you are going to get.
这就是你将要得到的。
The parent to do then and then tell trans something like.
然后父进程执行，并向子进程传递一些信息。
And however,
然而，
if you are asleep will something
如果你正在睡觉，会发生什么事情
change.
改变。
That's a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
So it was a question.
所以这是一个问题。
When is a child code executive?
一个子代码何时被执行？
When is the child called executive?
什么时候称为执行程序？
The child is a different process with the difference which is on stress.
这个孩子是一个不同的进程，与其他进程的不同之处在于它处于压力状态。
That's a good question.
这是一个很好的问题。
The answer is on the operating system is titled execute.
操作系统中的答案被称为执行。
The side of the other process is a schedule of deciding it.
另一个进程的一侧是决定它的调度计划。
That's exactly what the question tries to say.
这正是问题试图表达的意思。
But try to illustrate.
但是尽量进行说明。
If you just print one after another,
如果你只是一个接一个地打印，
then the code is green code.
那么这段代码是绿色的代码。
Can run fast enough.
可以跑得够快。
So it's not the process is not suspended.
所以进程并没有被挂起。
That's I likely what you are going to see,
这可能是你将要看到的。
you are going to see the parent consecutively printing from 1 to 10
你将会看到父进程连续打印从1到10的数字。
and then the child from 1 to 10
然后是从1到10的孩子。
or the other around.
或者反过来。
However, if you could sleep,
然而，如果你能睡觉的话，
then that's enough time for the parent to be suspended as a child running
那么这段时间足够让父进程暂停，作为一个正在运行的子进程。
and the other way around.
反过来也一样。
So we are going to see an interleave interleaving,
所以我们将要看到一个交错的交错。
the printer from the parent and the child.
来自父进程和子进程的打印机。
We are going to see them into living.
我们将会去看望他们。
It's another view.
这是另一种观点。
This is a view.
这是一个视图。
It's executing as an exact will talk a little bit about the exact.
它正在执行作为一个确切的，我们稍微谈谈确切的一点。
But for this purpose,
但是为了这个目的，
it's again, you say, see, here is a parent execute.
又是这样，你说，看，这里是一个父进程执行。
Now, look at the if function is reversed,
现在，让我们来看一下 if 函数被反转的情况，
if checks first,
如果先检查
whether the pid return from there is the return from the fork is zero.
从那里返回的pid是否是fork返回的零。
We know if the return is zero,
我们知道如果返回值为零，
the code is executed by the child.
代码由子进程执行。
This is exact.
这是准确的。
Lcpid different than zero,
Lcpid不为零，
hopefully is greater than zero than you, the parent.
希望的是，子进程的值大于零，而父进程的值不大于零。
It's a like, you think, white in this case.
这是一个类似的想法，你认为，在这种情况下是白色的。
And we are going to what exact is doing.
我们要做的具体是什么？
And we'll learn we'll talk more about it briefly.
我们将会简要地更多地讨论它。
Exact.
准确的。
It's running a program that program will replace the code of the child
它正在运行一个程序，该程序将替换子进程的代码。
with the program itself.
与程序本身相关。
Think about right now,
现在请你思考一下，
the fork replicated,
fork复制了进程，
duplicated the code of the parent to the child now is the exact we are
将父进程的代码复制到子进程中，现在它们完全相同。
just some sense of conceptually
只是一些概念上的理解
we override the child code with a code of the program we want to execute.
我们用我们想要执行的程序的代码覆盖子代码。
And this is what happens when you implement the shell.
当你实现shell时，会发生以下情况。
And you are going to do you do that in your homework?
你会在你的作业中这样做吗？
Right?
对吗？
What happened is a shell is a path, the shell,
发生的是一个shell是一个路径，即shell。
or you type in the comments.
或者你可以在评论中输入。
And you type your comment.
然后你输入你的评论。
Right?
对吗？
What happens?
发生了什么事情？
The shell process,
Shell进程，
forks, another process,
forks, 另一个进程,
and the 4th process is going to use exact to run the program you want to run.
第四个进程将使用exact来运行您想要运行的程序。
Okay?
好的？
This weight is similar with a join that join like its way it's waiting
这个权重类似于一个连接，就像它的方式一样，它在等待。
for the child to finish.
等待孩子完成。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
I'll answer the questions immediately.
我会立即回答这些问题。
So where it wait for process to finish,
它在等待进程完成的地方。
these are some other ap is exit,
这些是其他已退出的应用程序。
your terminates approach,
你的终止方法，
the process you have also exit for these threads.
你所拥有的进程也退出了这些线程。
Then you have this command which is killed.
然后你有一个被终止的命令。
I can kill a particular process.
我可以终止一个特定的进程。
If I send this kind of signal,
如果我发送这种信号，
like, for instance, the operating system,
例如，操作系统，
this is how it kills a process.
这是它如何终止一个进程的方式。
For one reason or another sends a kill signatory.
由于某种原因发送了一个终止信号。
And then if you are a process,
然后，如果你是一个进程，
you get aa aa signal,
你收到了一个 aa aa 信号。
then you can actually sometimes can do something about the signal.
在某些情况下，你实际上可以对信号采取一些措施。
We'll talk more about it.
我们会进一步讨论这个问题。
But this, again,
但是，再次提到这一点，
a simple program in which,
一个简单的程序，其中，
again, for acpid call zero everything within that branch.
再次，对于acpid调用，请将该分支内的所有内容归零。
It's executed by the child,
它由子进程执行。
so the child executive and gets it by apiid princess pid and then exit
所以子进程通过apiid princess pid获取它，然后退出。
with a42,
使用a42
which is a a it's a return code.
这是一个返回代码。
Whatever you want to pick,
无论你想选择什么，
the code executed by the parent.
由父进程执行的代码。
It's waiting for the child breaks.
它正在等待子进程结束。
This is a wait.
这是一个等待操作。
And now, like I mentioned,
现在，就像我之前提到的，
when you get an action as aaa signal,
当你收到一个名为aaa的信号时，
as a process,
作为一个进程，
you can do something about it.
你可以采取一些行动。
How you can do about it,
你对此有什么打算？
you intercept.
你拦截。
For instance, you get this is a sink interrupt.
例如，你收到了一个中断信号。
You can also send from a user process to another user process that can send
您还可以从一个用户进程发送到另一个可以发送的用户进程。
this signal.
这个信号。
And in basically,
基本上，
you can associate,
你可以关联
you can say that when you get this thing interrupt,
当你收到这个中断时，你可以这样说。
you are going to execute a piece of code.
你将要执行一段代码。
You write a function which execute this piece of code,
你需要编写一个函数来执行这段代码。
then use a secret action to pass the address of that function,
然后使用一个秘密操作来传递该函数的地址。
to be invoked when I seeking it's when you receive using the process
在接收到使用该进程时被调用的时候，我正在寻找它。
to receive the seeking that.
接收寻求请求。
Okay?
好的？
If you don't have registered for a seeking,
如果您还没有注册寻求帮助，
this call back to handle it,
这是一个回调函数来处理它。
the processors die.
处理器死机。
Right?
对吗？
As otherwise,
否则，
you may want to keep the process around and do something about it.
你可能希望保留该进程并对其进行一些操作。
There are many signals I told seeking seeking is also,
有很多信号我告诉寻求寻求也是的。
it's when you do ctrl c when you have a program and runs into controversy
当你在运行一个程序时，遇到争议时，你可以使用Ctrl+C。
that generate ac int,
生成交流电整数。
the program, if you don't do anything, it will be killed.
如果你不做任何操作，程序将被终止。
But if you do something,
但是如果你做了某事，
c control c you intercept it.
c 控制 c 你拦截它。
You doesn't need to kill the process.
你不需要终止该进程。
Six step,
六个步骤
its control z you stop the process.
按下Ctrl+Z可以暂停进程。
When you seek term is when you have a shell command and you want to kill it,
当你说"seek term"时，意思是你有一个shell命令，并且想要终止它。
there are secure and six stop to terminate the process.
有六个安全的终止进程的方法。
You cannot cannot intercept the cigar by cigar action.
你不能通过吸烟行为来拦截雪茄。
So this will terminate your process.
这将终止您的进程。
These are, in general,
总的来说，这些是
what is used by the operating system to terminate the process a process.
操作系统用什么来终止一个进程？
Let me just talk briefly here and see what are the questions.
让我简要地谈一下，看看有什么问题。
Rp set, mutex lock,
Rp集合，互斥锁
and the unlocking implement with a semi force is, again,
而使用半力解锁的实施方式是，再次，
is dependent on the operating system.
依赖于操作系统。
We are going to learn different implementation for lock and unlock.
我们将学习不同的锁定和解锁实现方式。
How do you know the scheduler one switch in the middle of the parents?
你是如何知道调度器在父进程中间进行切换的？
For look, you do not know.
对于外表，你并不了解。
And that's exactly the point.
这正是关键所在。
I said what I mentioned in the previous example that if you don't have
我在之前的例子中提到过，如果你没有...
the sleep with a high probability,
以高概率休眠。
what you are going to see is that the parent output from the parent,
你将要看到的是来自父进程的输出。
the follow up, the printing that ten values,
后续操作是打印十个值。
and then from the child.
然后从子进程开始。
But there is a very small probability that you can also be interrupted.
但是有很小的概率你也可能会被打断。
During that.
在那期间。
Look,
看着吧，
the point is that you insert the slips,
关键是你要插入这些纸条，
then now the entire loop will take you 10 seconds.
那么现在整个循环将花费你10秒的时间。
Therefore,
因此，
you are guaranteed to be interrupted by the child, the parent by the child,
你肯定会被孩子打断，父母也会被孩子打断。
and the child by the parent,
由父进程创建的子进程，
the child.
孩子。
So does the child always has apid zero?
孩子进程的进程ID（pid）是否总是为零？
Remember, the child is a process.
记住，孩子是一个进程。
The process has appeared as an identifier.
该进程已出现为一个标识符。
What we have is here, what we are on earth.
我们拥有的是此刻，我们存在于地球上。
See, talking here about the pid is a return of the fork function.
在这里谈论的是进程ID是fork函数的返回值。
Basically, the return for functions in the child process doesn't return.
基本上，子进程中的函数返回不会返回。
The child process.
子进程。
Id return is zero.
返回的id为零。
It doesn't mean the process id is zero.
这并不意味着进程ID为零。
In return, it mean, we are only saying that the fork, let me repeat.
回报意味着我们只是在说fork，让我重复一遍。
The fork is a child code returns when executed, return is zero.
当执行 fork 时，子代码返回的返回值为零。
When executing fork is apparent,
当执行fork时，显然
return,
返回,
child process identifier.
子进程标识符。
How does a parent on calling wait?
父进程在调用wait时会发生什么？
And now who to wait?
现在等谁呢？
Who to wait for?
等待谁？
Ii believe if I remember correctly,
我相信如果我记得正确的话，
the you can specify that in white.
你可以在白色中指定。
We'll see that.
我们会看到的。
Let me continue a little,
让我继续一下，
and i'll stop for more questions.
我会停下来等待更多问题。
The a shell a it's a job control system that it's what you're getting a terminal.
shell是一个作业控制系统，它是你在终端上使用的东西。
You have the prompt that the shell from there,
你可以在那里使用shell提示符。
you can execute other programs and or other comments.
你可以执行其他程序或添加其他注释。
You are going to build your own shell in homework, too.
你也要在作业中构建自己的shell。
And you are going to use a fork and exec to create new processes to create
你将使用fork和exec来创建新的进程。
programs like we mentioned earlier on,
我们之前提到的类似的程序，
right?
对的？
Your shell will fork a child,
你的shell将会fork一个子进程，
which will use exact to execute the program ok
这将使用exact来执行程序。
so this process versus threads.
所以这是进程与线程的比较。
One question here is why have four can exact system,
这里的一个问题是为什么需要四个精确的系统。
colorful processes,
多彩的进程
but just a piece thread create function for a thread.
但只是一个用于创建线程的函数片段。
The answer is here, but again, to summarize,
答案在这里，但是再次总结一下，
the main reason for that is that with threads,
主要原因是使用线程，
if one thread create another thread,
如果一个线程创建另一个线程，
the new thread share the circle and share the global variables and the heap,
新线程共享圆和共享全局变量以及堆内存。
which with a sandwich created it right?
这是一个有三明治的问题吗？
While in the case,
在这种情况下，
in the and then also the p thread,
在 "and then also the p thread" 中，
you give the crowd to execute,
你将任务交给人群执行，
right?
对的？
You give a new greater thread,
你创建了一个新的更大的线程。
you give the curve,
你给出了曲线。
the function to be executed by the thread.
线程要执行的函数。
In the case of fork,
在fork的情况下，
when you create a new process,
当你创建一个新的进程时，
because the new there is no sharing between two processes.
因为新的进程之间没有共享。
They have different other spaces.
它们有不同的其他空间。
You are going to duplicate the code and the resources from the parent
你需要复制父级的代码和资源。
to the child.
给孩子。
But now,
但是现在，
the parent and child execute the same code.
父进程和子进程执行相同的代码。
So to execute a different kind of code for a program, you need,
因此，要为程序执行不同类型的代码，你需要
you are going to call exact.
你打算打电话给谁？
Right?
对吗？
We speak.
我们说话。
There is no need for such that such thing.
没有必要这样做。
Because first of all,
首先，因为
there is no need for function id because they shared the threads share
不需要函数 id，因为线程共享它们的资源
the same address space.
相同的地址空间。
And then it's also,
然后还有一个问题，
when you create a thread,
当你创建一个线程时，
you.out to the few give also the address of the function,
你输出给少数人时，也要给出函数的地址。
the state should execute,
状态应该执行。
by the way, and as a note, in windows,
顺便提一下，在Windows操作系统中，
instead of what we have create process.
与我们创建进程的方式不同。
Here is a question for you.
这是一个问题给你。
If we have two tasks to run concurrently,
如果我们有两个任务需要同时运行，
do iran them in separate threads of iranians?
在伊朗，他们是否将伊朗人分成不同的线程？
In separate process?
在单独的进程中吗？
Again, I shouldn't have the head the answer here,
再次强调，我不应该在这里给出答案。
but it depends.
但这取决于情况。
Is how much isolation you want to have.
你想要多少隔离？
The threads are lighter weight.
线程的负担更轻。
Why is that lighter weight?
为什么它更轻量级？
Because they don't share all because they don't have a lot of state
因为它们不共享所有资源，因为它们没有很多状态。
associated with them.
与它们相关联。
So when you switch them,
所以当你切换它们时，
When the skipper switch from one side to another doesn't need to save
当船长从一侧切换到另一侧时，不需要保存
all the context.
所有的上下文。
Essentially, the process, it's just a teeny bit of context,
基本上，进程只是一点点的上下文信息。
especially the thread.
尤其是线程。
It's much faster.
它速度快多了。
On the other hand,
另一方面，
the process that is much stronger isolated.
更强烈隔离的进程。
Again, each process lives in its own other space.
同样，每个进程都存在于自己的独立空间中。
Let me just see a few more questions
让我再看几个问题。
since let's share other spaces,
既然让我们分享其他空间，
but nor stack,
但不是栈。
do the stack start a different offset, absolutely.
栈的起始偏移是不同的，绝对如此。
The stack.
栈。
They do that a different processes.
他们通过不同的进程来完成这个任务。
And if you remember from here, right?
如果你还记得的话，是从这里开始的，对吗？
From this figure,
从这个图中，
something is very slow.
某些东西非常慢。
Here you have two stacks,
这里有两个栈，
a the different.
一个不同的。
They start a different they have different stack pointers,
它们启动时有不同的栈指针。
start a different addresses.
从不同的地址开始。
Okay?
好的？
So let me see that I think there are some question about on the chat.
所以让我看看，我认为聊天中有一些问题。
Yes, the new stack frames,
是的，新的栈帧，
the new stacks out in the same address space,
新的栈在相同的地址空间中。
but start at different points and different addresses.
但是从不同的起点和不同的地址开始。
What happens to the stack when you make a new thread?
当你创建一个新线程时，栈会发生什么变化？
When you create a new thread,
当你创建一个新线程时，
you create a new stack for that thread.
你为该线程创建一个新的栈。
We should not interfere with the stack of the current strategy.
我们不应该干涉当前策略的堆栈。
I think it's pretty much it if I didn't answer any questions because that
如果我没有回答任何问题，我认为这就差不多了。
is connect and everything else.
是连接和其他一切。
Let me know some announcements.
请告诉我一些公告。
The project zero is the project zero is due this thursday.
项目零的截止日期是本周四。
Today from now,
从现在开始的今天，
it's again, it needs to be done on your own like homework.
这次又是一样的，需要你自己完成，就像作业一样。
Is the only one you need to do on your own.
这是你唯一需要自己完成的任务。
All the other projects are group projects.
所有其他项目都是小组项目。
Group assignments will be released by end of day this wednesday.
小组作业将在本周三的最后一天发布。
A discussion,
一次讨论
a section attendance is mandatory and with cameras on if you are remarked
某个部分的出勤是强制性的，并且如果你被注意到了，摄像头会开启。
and start already planning with your group how to best collaborate on the project,
并且开始与你的小组一起计划如何最好地在项目上进行合作，
especially if you are remote,
尤其是如果你是远程的，
virtual coffee hours with a camera,
使用摄像头进行虚拟咖啡时间
regular brainstorm meeting,
定期头脑风暴会议
and try to meet multiple times a week.
并尝试每周多次见面。
Most of the problems between from our experience with the groups happens
我们在与团队合作的经验中遇到的大部分问题都源于此。
because communication.
因为沟通。
It turns out that not everyone in the group is on the same page,
结果发现，小组中并不是每个人都意见一致，
not everyone understood the same thing like what everyone has to do and buy
并不是每个人都理解得一样，就像每个人都要做什么和买什么一样。
what and what to do.
是什么和要做什么。
So over communicate over community,
所以要在社区中进行过度沟通，
there is nothing like too much communication for your group to be successful
对于团队的成功来说，没有过多的沟通这样的事情。
for the rest of this lecture,
在本节课的剩余时间里，
we are starting to talk about.
我们开始讨论。
We are diving into file systems, file abstraction.
我们正在深入研究文件系统和文件抽象化。
In particular,
特别是，
we are only going to talk about high level file io and these are streams.
我们只会讨论高级文件输入输出，这些是流。
We are going to talk more about files next lecture on saturday.
我们下一堂课将更多地讨论文件的内容，时间是周六。
So now,
所以现在，
basically,
基本上，
we are a lot of concepts we are going to work on are inherited
我们要讨论的许多概念都是继承而来的。
from original unix.
来自原始的Unix。
And indeed, why not linux is unique?
为什么 Linux 是独一无二的呢？
Like we discussed ios or out mac os it's on top.
正如我们讨论的那样，iOS或者我们的macOS是顶级操作系统。
It's a unique system of the call and even windows.
这是一个独特的调用系统，甚至与Windows不同。
It's now more and more similar to you to unix.
它现在越来越像Unix了。
Then it was 20 years ago.
那是20年前的事了。
The main.about the unix,
关于Unix的主要内容是什么？
and this is brilliant idea at this day,
而且这是一个在今天非常出色的想法。
is to provide as much as possible a homogeneous abstraction across
的目标是尽可能提供一个统一的抽象层面，使其尽量一致。
different io devices.
不同的输入输出设备。
And that concept is about a five,
这个概念是关于一个五的概念。
which is a stream of bytes.
这是一个字节流。
This is not only the files on your disk,
这不仅仅是你磁盘上的文件，
but also the way you operate.
还有你的操作方式。
And the api when you send messages or receive messages,
发送消息或接收消息时的API
or you send data up to the send a file to the printer to be printed,
或者你将数据发送到打印机以打印文件。
or you get input from the terminal.
或者你从终端获取输入。
All of these,
所有这些，
you interact with all of these different devices in a very similar way.
你与所有这些不同的设备以非常相似的方式进行交互。
You can think, again,
你可以再次思考一下，
at a high level that everything is a file and you interact with them,
在高层次上，一切皆为文件，你与它们进行交互。
the base system calls then are open,
然后基本系统调用是open，
read, write, and close.
读取、写入和关闭。
It's open, file, clothes, file,
它是开着的，文件，衣服，文件，
read from file, write a file,
从文件中读取，写入文件。
some of the devices, so not have some of these operations.
有些设备可能不具备某些操作功能。
Like for instance, for a printer,
例如，对于打印机来说，
you have open,
你已经打开了。
call close and write, not read.
调用 close 和 write，而不是 read。
For the input terminal, you have read, but not write.
对于输入终端，你可以读取但不能写入。
Okay.
好的。
And then you have also this kind of cached all apiiocepl
然后你还有这种缓存所有apiiocepl的方式
for to customary configured different devices.
为了适应不同的设备进行常规配置。
Right?
对吗？
It's again for people who are interested in a little bit of history.
这是给对历史有一点兴趣的人们的再次提醒。
And actually to get given is very useful given for this class to get
实际上，获得这个课程的指导非常有用。
come context about how things evolved and why you can read this unique,
关于事物如何演变以及为什么你能阅读这个独特的内容的一些背景信息
the unix time sharing system,
Unix时间共享系统，
which is very old book that is almost 50 years,
这是一本非常古老的书，已经有将近50年的历史了。
very old paper.
非常古老的论文。
But it's extremely influential paper.
但这是一篇非常有影响力的论文。
And it's quite amazing.
而且这真是令人惊叹。
It's again, we are still using the same concept,
又是这个问题，我们仍然在使用相同的概念。
fundamentally like this paper described,
基本上就像这篇论文所描述的那样，
again, almost 50 years ago.
再说一次，将近50年前。
If you have1 hour,
如果你有1小时的时间，
this is a fantastic paper of it.
这是一篇非常棒的论文。
You'll hear more about politics.
你将会听到更多关于政治的事情。
What is politics is portable operating system?
什么是可移植操作系统？
Interface, excuse me, for unix.
接口，对不起，针对Unix操作系统。
It defines kind of a standard.
它定义了一种标准。
It's an effort of standardizing.
这是一种标准化的努力。
It was an effort to standardize different unix flavors.
这是为了标准化不同的Unix版本而做出的努力。
27 or 25 years ago,
27年或25年前，
there are a lot of unique flavors,
有很多独特的口味。
different companies.
不同的公司。
They have their own unique version.
他们有自己独特的版本。
Politics was the effort to standardize a subset of ap is across this.
政治是在这个领域中努力标准化一部分应用程序的努力。
Unix is okay.
Unix很好。
So the file of file system abstraction.
文件系统抽象的文件。
So it's a name collection of data in a file system.
所以它是文件系统中的一个数据名称集合。
And the posits file data is a sequence of bikes.
posits文件中的数据是一系列自行车的序列。
Could be text binary.
可以是文本二进制化。
You can have a serialized objects, almost anything.
你可以序列化几乎任何对象。
In addition to the file data,
除了文件数据之外，
you have meta data.
你有元数据。
And the meta data associated with a file,
以及与文件相关的元数据，
contain things like the size of the file.
包含文件的大小等信息。
When was the last time modified?
最后一次修改是什么时候？
Who is our owner?
我们的所有者是谁？
Security information who has access control and so forth.
安全信息，包括访问控制等。
The files are stored in folders,
文件存储在文件夹中，
right?
对的？
The folder contains farthest and directory.
该文件夹包含最远和目录。
A director is a special kind of fire,
导演是一种特殊的火焰，
and the directories are organized in an article fashion,
目录以文章的方式进行组织，
as you very well know.
正如你非常了解的那样。
Okay.
好的。
There are also concepts of links and volumes,
还有链接和卷的概念。
hard links of links.
链接的硬链接。
We are going to learn about those later.
我们稍后会学习这些内容。
Now,
现在，
every process has its own current working directory.
每个进程都有自己的当前工作目录。
Okay?
好的？
When you start aaa program from a current directory,
当你从当前目录启动 aaa 程序时，
that typically is a current working directory of that program.
通常是该程序的当前工作目录。
So if you just read and write without providing a path.
如果您只是读取和写入而没有提供路径。
Then you read and write on the current director.
那么你可以在当前目录下进行读写操作。
Now,
现在，
you can also refer like you very well known to a file using the absolute directory.
你也可以使用绝对路径来引用你非常熟悉的文件。
In that case, the current direct working directory it's ignored.
在这种情况下，当前的直接工作目录将被忽略。
Again,
请再次说明您的问题。
the current talking director you can see thinking
当前的对话导演正在思考中。
about like an environment variable,
关于环境变量，
right?
是的，正确的。
Which is set when the program is started.
程序启动时设置的是什么？
And you can have relative specify relative paths to the current directory.
你可以使用相对路径来指定相对于当前目录的路径。
But I dot slash means you go one level up
但是"../"表示你向上一级。
and deal.
并处理。
That means home directory and so forth.
这意味着主目录等等。
And the storage,
还有存储设备，
it's actually a has a pretty complex architecture.
它实际上具有相当复杂的架构。
It goes all the way from io drivers,
它从io驱动程序开始，一直延伸到...
and this is controlled all these devices.
并且这个控制所有这些设备。
Then you have the file system which is implemented,
然后你有一个已经实现的文件系统。
functionally implementing the operating system.
功能性地实现操作系统。
That is called,
那被称为，
this is the interface provided by the operating system through which
这是操作系统提供的接口，通过它可以进行以下操作：
the user level programs can invoke
用户级程序可以调用
file system operations.
文件系统操作。
Then you have the low level io and high level io in provide
提供的功能中有低级IO和高级IO。
different levels of abstractions of the file system to the application.
文件系统对应用程序的不同抽象层级。
So here we are going to start from a high level io right?
所以我们要从高级 I/O 开始吗？
And again,
再次，
a stream is a sequence of bytes.
流是一系列字节的序列。
That's it.
就是这样。
Right?
对吗？
And how you open a file for in the stream format for this a with a stream
如何以流格式打开文件并使用流进行操作？
api you use f open,
你使用的 API 是 f open。
you include sto this represents containers contains the api
你可以使用 `#include ` 来引入包含 API 的容器。
the file related file stream file ap is f open,
与文件流相关的文件AP是fopen。
obviously, is part of sdo dot h and as the of open take,
显然，它是sdo.h的一部分，并且作为open函数的一部分被调用。
several arguments,
几个参数
one is a file name,
一个是文件名
right?
对的？
Which is the name of the file.
文件的名称是什么？
And here you can, especially if you don't specify the pass.
在这里你可以这样做，尤其是如果你没有指定密码。
Again, you are referring to a file in the current directory.
再次强调，你正在引用当前目录中的文件。
If you specify an absolute path,
如果您指定了绝对路径，
then is a current directory ignore.
当前目录被忽略。
And you have also a mode,
而且你还有一个模式，
right?
对的？
The mode, it tells,
模式，它告诉
basically,
基本上，
what is this?
这是CS162计算机操作系统的助教。
What you can do is this file.
你可以做的是这个文件。
Right?
对吗？
You can,
你可以。
what kind of file is this one?
这是什么类型的文件？
You can have text files or binary files, right?
你可以有文本文件或二进制文件，对吗？
With the text files,
使用文本文件，
the code is interpreted as being a character with a binary file is a bike.
这段代码被解释为一个字符，二进制文件是一辆自行车。
Sorry, that it's not interpreter.
抱歉，这不是一个解释器。
It's not interpreted when you print it,
当你打印它时，它不会被解释。
when you try to print it.
当你尝试打印它时。
In addition from the type of that is of the fibers that is text or binary,
除了文本或二进制类型的纤维之外，
what is the kind of operation which are allowed on the fire?
火可以进行哪些操作？
R is for it,
R代表它，
right?
是的，正确的。
Is for obviously modifying,
这是显然要进行修改的。
append.
追加。
It's for writing only at the end of the file.
这是用于在文件末尾进行写入的。
Then you can write,
那么你可以写：
you can also open a file boss for read and write.
你也可以打开一个文件，用于读取和写入。
You can also take into account what happens if I open a file,
你还可以考虑一下如果我打开一个文件会发生什么。
but the file doesn't take this.
但是文件不接受这个。
You can get an error file not found, or you can.
你可能会遇到文件未找到的错误。
I have a use another option to say if it file doesn't exist created
如果文件不存在，我可以使用另一种选项来创建它。
and as an amplifier.
并且作为一个放大器。
Right?
对吗？
So when you open the file, what you are,
当你打开文件时，你所做的是什么？
you are going to get a pointer to the file data structure.
你将获得一个指向文件数据结构的指针。
Also, you are going to get a pointer, right?
另外，你会得到一个指针，对吧？
You represent the state of the file.
你代表文件的状态。
Open file is represented by the pointer and it to the current byte
打开文件由指针表示，并指向当前字节。
in the file that you are going to read or write.
在你要读取或写入的文件中。
There are also several specialized files,
还有几种专门的文件类型，
standard being standard doubt, standard error.
标准是标准，怀疑是标准错误。
Okay?
好的？
Standard beam is,
标准梁是一种常见的结构元素，通常用于支撑和传递负载。它通常具有长方形或I形的截面，可以根据需要定制长度和尺寸。标准梁通常由钢材或木材制成，具有高强度和刚性，能够承受大量的重量和压力。它们广泛应用于建筑、桥梁、机械设备和其他工程领域。
obviously from input,
显然从输入中，
from the terminal sound out.
从终端发出声音。
It's also when you write out to the terminal standard error when you write
当你写入标准错误输出时，也是这样。
and is error.
并且是错误的。
And again,
再次，
the important point to now here,
这里需要注意的重点是，
it's again, is treated all this input from your keyboard output,
再次强调，所有从键盘输入的内容都会被处理并输出。
the terminal.
终端。
They are all treated as fires.
它们都被视为火灾。
And this standard being a standard out enable composition in unix.
这个标准使得在Unix中能够进行标准输出的组合。
Because everything is a file.
因为一切皆为文件。
Therefore, you can pipe.
因此，你可以使用管道。
You can create a pipeline of commands,
你可以创建一个命令的流水线。
because in general,
因为一般来说，
each command is going to read from a file and write to a file.
每个命令都会从一个文件中读取数据，并将结果写入另一个文件中。
For instance, here you have cat, hello text, grab word.
例如，这里有cat、hello text和grab word。
What does it mean?
这句话的意思是什么？
Cat, hello text is basically is going to,
Cat, 你好文本基本上是要去的。
if you just execute that is going to write on the terminal the content
如果你只是执行，它会将内容写入终端。
of the file,
文件的
hello dot x but because determine the content,
你好，由于无法确定内容，
what hello the standard out where the file is written,
标准输出是指文件被写入的位置。
it's also a file.
它也是一个文件。
You can pipe in the grip world,
你可以在grep命令中使用管道操作符。
which take as the input of a file to look for the occurrences of the world.
该程序以文件作为输入，用于查找单词的出现次数。
Exclamation.,
感叹词。
exclamation mark.
感叹号。
A a little bit more.
再多一点点。
The api is a little bit richer.
这个 API 更加丰富一些。
Once you open it,
一旦你打开它，
you can do aaa lot of things with the data in that file,
你可以对那个文件中的数据做很多事情。
f for c right?
是的，fahrenheit 转换为 celsius。
It puts a character.
它输出一个字符。
It's writes a character as a current location in the file.
它将一个字符写入文件的当前位置。
Right?
对吗？
Remember, this fp is returned by f open,
记住，这个fp是由fopen返回的。
this pointer to the file data structures.
这个指针指向文件数据结构。
F put s an entire string,
F put s 将整个字符串放入
a set of characters, which end with a zero.
一组以零结尾的字符。
In the file from the current position,
从当前位置开始的文件中，
f get c and f get s goods are reversing,
f get c 和 f get s 的货物颠倒了。
read from the current position in the file,
从文件的当前位置开始读取数据。
or read from the current position for a set,
或者从当前位置开始读取一组数据，
for for a given set of characters.
给定一组字符。
So greece,
希腊，
a given set of characters from the given position and put them in a string.
从给定位置开始，将给定字符集合中的字符取出并放入一个字符串中。
When you are going to write global to the current position,
当你要将全局变量写入当前位置时，
the current position is implemented.
当前位置已实现。
If you are going to that to call for efforts,
如果你打算这样呼吁努力的话，
multiple times is not going to overwrite.
多次操作不会覆盖。
Write in the same position.
以同样的位置写下来。
It writes as a subsequent position.
它作为一个后续位置进行写入。
This first set of ap is are character oriented.
这一组应用程序是面向字符的。
Then we have block oriented if you can operate on a bunch of elements.
如果您可以对一组元素进行操作，那么我们就有了块导向（block oriented）的操作。
This is, if you think about is very useful and you have records,
这是一个非常有用的功能，如果你考虑到它并且有记录的话。
your file is a bunch of records,
你的文件是一堆记录，
right?
对的？
She's like poor man database,
她就像一个贫穷的人类数据库，
but I do have records.
但是我确实有记录。
Then you want to read and write a bunch of records of the time.
然后你想要读取和写入一堆时间记录。
In this case, you need to give the number of the elements you want,
在这种情况下，您需要提供您想要的元素的数量。
the number of records you want to read, right?
你想要读取的记录数量，对吗？
And also the size of each record.
还有每个记录的大小。
And then the last A it's of AP is are format it.
然后最后一个A是AP的格式。
But I remember when you do a print f right?
但是我记得你是用 printf 对吧？
You are going to format the string,
你要对字符串进行格式化。
right?
对的？
The output string.
输出字符串。
And f scan f is, again,
而f扫描f是再次的。
it reads a formatted string.
它读取一个格式化的字符串。
Okay?
好的？
This is an example of having a character by character io this is about reading,
这是一个逐字符进行输入输出的示例，关于读取。
copying from an input to an output.
从输入复制到输出。
You get your open input and output files files.
你可以获取你的输入和输出文件。
Then you get one character from the input,
然后你从输入中获取一个字符，
and then you write the character to the output.
然后你将字符写入输出。
And then once you are done,
然后一旦你完成了，
then you close the input and the output.
然后你关闭输入和输出。
So that and how do you know is done?
那么，你是如何知道这件事已经完成了呢？
When you run, when you get to the end of the files,
当你运行时，当你到达文件的末尾时，
you get a year end of file eof
你遇到了文件末尾 (EOF)
this is an example,
这是一个例子，
again, to do blog blog by blog io in this case, again,
再次，在这种情况下，通过博客IO来完成博客的操作。再次。
you opened again to input and output.
你再次打开了输入和输出。
And now you are going to,
现在你要做的是，
right,
好的，
in this case,
在这种情况下，
you write by,
你写的是什么？
like, I like,
喜欢，我喜欢，
array of bytes or you read array of bytes.
字节数组或者你读取字节数组。
Do you have a buffer size?
你有缓冲区大小吗？
And say this is, I don't know, it's 10, 24,
这是，我不知道，是10点24分。
so it's one kilobyte.
所以它是一千字节。
You write the size of each record.
你需要写下每个记录的大小。
It's one character.
这是一个字符。
Right?
对吗？
Here, you are going to,
在这里，你将要
again,
再次，
to read and write from a file at the level of a brighter blog granularity,
在更高级别的粒度上从文件中读取和写入数据
where a blog granularity, again, a buffer granularity,
博客的粒度是指博客的大小或范围，而缓冲区的粒度是指缓冲区的大小或范围。
which is he had one kilobyte.
他拥有一个千字节。
It's again,
又是这样，
this is most and I'm going to end up with this.
这是最后的结果，我将以此结束。
This is for you to keep in mind when you are going to work on the homework,
这是你在开始做作业时需要记住的事情。
when you are going to work on the projects,
你打算什么时候开始做这些项目？
be paranoid, try to be defensive,
保持警惕，尽量采取防御措施，
try to think hard,
努力思考一下，
and try to capture every error.
并尝试捕获每个错误。
Right?
对吗？
That's why you call us function call when you call on,
这就是为什么当你调用函数时，你称之为函数调用。
or when you open a file and so forth.
或者当你打开一个文件等等。
Just check for errors.
请检查是否有错误。
This will save you a lot of pain,
这将为你节省很多痛苦，
even if you need to write a few more line of code,
即使你需要写几行额外的代码，
and this will also add you a better grade.
这也会给你增加更好的成绩。
Please check on the return values.
请检查返回值。
Let's stop here.
我们停在这里吧。
We'll just this one.
我们只需要这一个。
What we done,
我们所做的是什么？
what we learned here is we learn about the threads are the os unit
我们在这里学到的是线程是操作系统的基本单位。
of concurrency and abstract a
并发性和抽象化
virtual CPU and the threat contains all the state related to its executions.
虚拟CPU包含与其执行相关的所有状态信息。
And the processes contain over more threads and another space.
而进程中包含了更多的线程和另外的空间。
And all assets, all the threads in the same process.
所有资源，以及同一进程中的所有线程。
They share the same code and the same variables,
它们共享相同的代码和相同的变量。
global variables, all the global variables,
全局变量，所有的全局变量，
and the politics tidy.
并且政治整洁。
Everything is a file.
一切皆文件。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
So I see no new questions.
所以我看到没有新的问题。
So with this will end up and see you all on Saturday.
所以就这样结束了，周六见。
Thank you.
谢谢你。